Kristin Partridge

Grade 1 and Early Years Educator | IB PYP | Reggio-Inspired Practitioner | International Experience

Email: krisridge17@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristin-partridge-1631957

Professional Summary

A trusted and deeply experienced international school teacher leader. Proven ability to collaborate effectively with students, teachers and parent communities to promote the mission and vision of the school. Committed to inquiry-based, constructivist education. Demonstrated record of success in a variety of key roles spanning IB Programs and American curriculum schools. Student-centered, with a high value placed on creating caring, culturally inclusive classrooms. Believes that school communities that value international-mindedness and build personal connections can create conditions that will inspire the next generation of global citizens as responsible stewards of our world.

Core Competencies

- IB PYP Curriculum & Leadership
- Early Childhood & Grade 1 Education
- Reggio Emilia Philosophy
- Constructivist & Inquiry-Based Learning
- Inclusive & Culturally Responsive Classrooms
- Staff & Student Mentorship
- Workshop Presentation & Facilitation
- Whole School Curriculum Committees
- Parent and Community Engagement
- DEIJ & Wellbeing Initiatives

Key Achievements & Strengths

Pedagogical Leadership: Head of Department, Grade Level Leader, and Faculty Advisory Committee Member.

Workshop Leader: Presented at EARCOS and regional conferences in Vietnam, Taiwan, and the Philippines.

Reggio Emilia Advocate: Reggio-inspired curriculum implementation and workshop facilitation in multiple schools.

Community Contribution: Led Sunshine and Social Committees, organized school summer camps, and coordinated new faculty onboarding.

Certifications

- IB PYP Training:
- Making the PYP Happen
- Teacher as Researcher
- Assessment in the Early Years
- Symbolic Learning: Literacy and Numeracy in the Early Years
- Personal, Social and Physical Education-Well Being
- Play Based Learning (2012 & 2017)
- Reggio Emilia Study Tours: 2006 and 2021
- Cognitive Coaching: Days 1-4
- Responsive Classroom Training
- Project Zero Harvard: Making Learning Visible
- Additional PD: Erin Kent, Fiona Hamilton, Anne van Dam, Opal School, Lynn Erickson, and others

Professional Experience

Grade 1 Teacher

2024 - Present

KIS Reignwood Park, Thailand

Grade 1 Teacher, Head of Department

2022 - 2024

Kaohsiung American School, Taiwan

Early Years Homeroom Teacher (Ages 3-7), Grade 1 & EY Leader

2016 - 2022

United Nations International School Hanoi, Vietnam

Early Years Homeroom Teacher

2014 - 2016

International School of Tianjin, China

Pre-K Homeroom Teacher, Early Years Coordinator

2011 - 2014

Jakarta World Academy / Sinarmas World Academy

Early Childhood Consultant (Ongoing)

2000 - Present

Early Childhood School Director, Assistant Director, Teacher

1996 - 2009

Stroum Jewish Community Centre, Seattle, WA

Leadership and Workshops

- IB Dunia and EARCOS Workshop Leader (Jakarta, Malaysia, Vietnam, Taiwan)
- Organizer & Leader of "Day of Dialogue" and Reggio Emilia Network (Seattle)
- Social Committee Chair UNIS Hanoi and IST Tianjin
- DEIJ Committee Member
- Workshop Leader IB Job Alike, IB Dunia, Learning Together (Vietnam)
- Mentor Teacher Student Teacher Practicum, University of Washington
- Community Outreach Facilitator Kajol Program, Grade 5 Exhibition Mentor

Education

- Master of Arts in Management, University of Phoenix 2004
- Bachelor of Applied Science in Elementary Education, University of Minnesota, Duluth